Mss.Ms.Coll.97
American Philosophical Society
- IV. Native American Cultures and Languages, 2.0 Linear feet (Box 28-31)
  - Records of the Colony of New Plymouth, or Acts of the Commissioners of the United Colonies of New England, 25.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Records of the Town of Jamaica Long Island, New York, 1656-1751, 5.0 p. (Box 30)
  - References -- Indians of New England, 4.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Notes on Burial and Related Customs, 1931-1932; 3.0 p.; Riste, Victor (Box 30)
  - Shawnee Bibliography, n.d.; 20.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Shawnee Vocabulary, n.d.; 22.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Shinnecock Vocabulary, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Siouan and Caddoan Linguistics, Issue No. 5, 1985; 29.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Western Woods Cree: Anthropological Myth and Historical Reality, 1987; 16.0 p.; Smith, James G. E. (Box 30)
    American Anthropologist, vol. 14, no. 3
  - Switch-Reference in Conchucos Quechua: Beyond Adverbial, 1986; 6.0 p.; Stewart, Anne M. (Box 30)
    Haas Festival Conference
  - Position of Apalachee in Muskogean Ball Games, 1986; 2.0 p.; Sturtevant, William C. (Box 30)
  - Summary of Words, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 30)
    Brief summary of vocabulary words in Eskimo, Sioux, Choctaw, and Nahuatl
  - Gros Ventre Dictionary, 1994; 3.0 Volume(s); Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931- (Box 31)
    Prefinal Version
    - Gros Ventre Dictionary, Volume 1, A - L, 1994; 516.0 p.; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931- (Box 31)
    - Gros Ventre Dictionary, Volume 2, M - Z, 1994; 484.0 p.; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931- (Box 31)
    - Gros Ventre Dictionary, Volume 3, Gros Ventre Stem Index, 1994; 132.0 p.; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931- (Box 31)
  - Children's Teeth, n.d.; 1.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
    Includes one sentence of Oklahoma Delaware
  - Linguistic Institute Course in Living Language, 1939; 7.0 folders; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
    Group for Delaware (an Algonquian Language) at the Linguistic Institute
    - Folder 1. Clusters in Delaware, 3 July 1939; 13.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
    - Folder 2. Sequences of VyV, 10 July 1939; 6.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
    - Folder 3. Inanimate Noun; Possession, 17 July 1939; 9.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
      Includes a text with translation, Mermaid Story
    - Folder 4. Class I of An. Intr. Verbs; Lengthened Vowel in 3d Person, 24 July 1939; 7.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
      Includes two texts in Delaware: Punishment for Disbelief in Mermaid; Mhuwe, the Cannibal
    - Folder 5. Normal n and Defective N- (The Letter Suggested by Dr. Frank Siebert), 31 July 1939; 8.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
      Includes text in Delaware: Mhuwe, the Cannibal (continued)
    - Folder 6. Tr. An. Indep., 7 August 1939; 7.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
    - Folder 7. Tr. Inan. Indep., 14 August 1939; 7.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
  - Siouan Notes, n.d.; 86.0 p.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
  - Effect of Language Change and Death on Obviation in Michif, 4.0 p.; Weaver, Deborah (Box 31)
  - Plains Cree Paradigms, 1970; 2.0 p.; Wolfart, H. Christoph (Box 31)
  - Unspecified Agents in the 18th Century, 1981; 2.0 p.; Wolfart, H. Christoph (Box 31)
  - World Languages, 18.0 p.
  - William Strachey, Historie of Travell into Virginia Brittania; Algonkin DIctionary; Manuscript Comparison, 1952; 49.0 p.; Wright, Louis B., (Louis Booker), 1899-1984 (Box 31)
  - Yenisei and Kotti, from M. A. Castren, 107.0 p. (Box 31)
    Handwritten notes from M. A. Castren, "Yenissei-Ostiak Dictionary" (St. Petersburg, 1849).
  - Yenisei and Kotti Vocabularies, 68.0 p. (Box 31)
- V. Notebooks, 6.5 Linear feet
  - Algonkin Linguistic Notes and Material, S: 31; 180.0 p.
  - Algonkin Notes, 1936; S: 88; 80.0 p. (Box 19)
  - Algonquian Miscellaneaous Notes, 1938-1940; S: 90-92; 3.0 folders (Box 19)
    - Volume 1, 1938; S: 90; 80.0 p. (Box 19)
    - Volume 2, 1940; S: 91; 81.0 p. (Box 19)
    - Volume 3, 1940; S: 92; 81.0 p. (Box 19)
  - Arapaho, Gros Ventre Notes, n.d.; 46.0 p.
    Vocabulary; songs composed by Chief Yellowcalf
  - Arthur Neptune / 95, Val Ranco
    Penobscot words (few), reading notes
  - Aubery, Book I, 1972; S: 59a; 114.0 p.
    Left side, Penobscot; Right side, Aubery Eastern Abenaki - French manuscript dictionary
  - Aubery, Book II, n.d.; S: 59b; 44.0 p.
  - British Museum and Bodleian Library Manuscripts, 9.0 p.
    Reading notes of manuscripts including Collonel John Scott's Preface to an Intended History of America; and, Commission of Indian Affairs, Albany, 1707.
  - Delaware Texts, 1935; 42.0 p.
  - Eliot Bible Reconstruction / Analysis, n.d.; S: 115; 241.0 p.
  - Eliot Bible Reconstruction / Analysis, n.d.; S: 116; 28.0 p.
  - English Words, Usage, and Grammatical Notes, 1936; 159.0 p.
  - Ethnology Notes, 1937; 150.0 p.
    - Ball game rackets, 1937
  - French Census (1708), Penobscot Names and Translations, S: 58; 16.0 p.
  - General Linguistics, 1935; S: 122; 134.0 p.
  - General Mythology; North American and Algonquian Mythology and Folklore, 1936; S: 89; 60.0 p. (Box 15)
  - Historical Events and Various Matters, 1970; 110.0 p.
    Includes notations on Proclamation of 1763; Treaty of Fort Niagara 1764; Treaty of Hard Labor 1768; Proclamation by Governor of Virginia 1791; Bibliography; etc.
  - Historical Logs from Various Authors and Volumes, 1963; 88.0 p.
    Historical notes largely concerning the Catawba; George Washington letters
  - Indian, 1931; 45.0 p. (Box 15)
    Notebook with notes on Maine history
  - Indian Mills, Addresses, Vocabulary, 1937, n.d.; 35.0 p.
    Vocabulary is counting from one to ten in numerous languages,
  - Indians, 1929; 146.0 p. (Box 15)
    Notebook with notes on history, and to a lesser extent, vocabulary and texts. Passamaquoddy, Abenaki.
  - Injunctive, n.d.; S: 54; 12.0 p.
    Penobscot
  - Language Research Notes (Phonetics), n.d.; 232.0 p.
    Phonetics, history of phonetics. Various sources and vocabularies. European languages: {emphasis} Spanish, Portugese, French; {other} English, Latin, Italian. Native American: Penobscot vowels
  - Linguistic and Phonetic Notes, 1928; S: 123; 45.0 p.
    Includes notes on language and grammar; classification of Algonquian languages
  - Linguistic Notes, 1937; S: 120; 114.0 p.
    Notes on language, general linguistics, and grammar with definitions of terms. Classifications of languages around the world, including Africa and Asia. Word lists of Yanna language, from Sapir, etc.
  - Linguistic Notes, S: 121; 157.0 p.
    Contains a wide array of notes on linguistics, theory, various languages (Tocharian, Hittite, Basque, etc.), the evolution of languages, language of children, etc.
  - Linguistic Notes on Proto-Algonquian, n.d.; S: 87; 116.0 p. (Box 21)
  - Linguistic Notes, Quapaw and Cherokee, 1962; 68.0 p.
    Also contains information on Fox
  - Maine History, Vocabulary, Fishes, n.d.; 272.0 p. (Box 16)
  - Maine Natural History, n.d.; 4.0 folders (Box 16)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; S: 77; 320.0 p. (Box 16)
      Notes on birds, vegetation, plants, infectious diseases in primitive societies. Many Penobscot words; Eastern Abenaki dialect words from Joseph Aubery and Sebastien Rale dictionaries
    - Folder 2, n.d.; S: 78; 258.0 p. (Box 16)
      Notes on plants and vegetation of Maine, with sketches. Includes notes on Penobscot census, genealogy.
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 384.0 p. (Box 16)
      Notes on plants, animals, bodies of water
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 19.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
      Clippings found in notebook which is now housed in Folder 3
  - Massachusetts, n.d.; 11.0 p.
    Linguistic notes
  - Menominee, n.d.; S: 93; 114.0 p.
    Vocabulary, linguistic notes, and analysis. In addition to Menominee, notebook contains material related to Cree, Ojibwa, and Penobscot. Vocabulary lists of insects, birds, animals, fish, trees, berries, plants, and relationships
  - Miscellaneous Vocabulary Book #1, S: 65; 219.0 p.
    Word sets; revisions; comparative vocabulary
  - Miscellaneous Vocabulary Book #2, n.d.; S: 66; 226.0 p.
  - Miscellaneous Vocabulary Book #3, n.d.; S: 67; 198.0 p.
  - Miscellaneous Vocabulary Book #4, n.d.; S: 68; 282.0 p.
    Word sets; revisions; Susie Dana ("S.D.")
  - Miscellaneous Vocabulary Book #5, n.d.; S: 69; 280.0 p.
    Word sets; revisions
    - Canoe paddles, 1932-1946
  - Miscellaneous Vocabulary Book #6, n.d.; S: 55; 301.0 p.
    Eastern Abenaki, Penobscot. Sillery Anonymous mansucript dictionary (Eastern Abenaki - French). Andrew Dana, Susie Dana, Madeleine Shay
  - Mohican Vocabulary, n.d.; S: 114; 4.0 Item(s)
    Includes Mohican Vocabulary, taken from Thomas Jefferson's fragmentary comparative vocabularies, omitting words that Jefferson copied from Heckewelder and adapted to the English orthography
  - More Penobscot Ethnohistory, n.d.; S: 44; 26.0 p. (Box 16)
  - Munsee Field Notes from Nicodemus Peters, Smoothtown, Six Nations' Reserve, Ontario, 1938; 127.0 p.
    Includes vocabulary and cultural notes on Delaware--beliefs and ceremonies
  - Munsee Speakers, 1939; 19.0 p.
    Includes Vocabulary
  - Natural History, n.d.; S: 76; 126.0 p. (Box 21)
    Notes on fish and vegetation, primarily from Maine and New England
  - New York and New England History, 13.0 Item(s)
    Series of examination booklets with notes on historical sources
  - Oklahoma Delaware. Various Speakers, Words, Names, Verbs, Numbers..., n.d.; 62.0 p.
  - Passamaquoddy, Micmac, Abenaki, Penobscot, Kenebec, Illinois, n.d.; 38.0 p. (Box 21)
    Vocabulary
  - Penobscot, 1933-1934; 145.0 p.
    Penobscot texts, reading notes, conversations, translations
  - Penobscot-Algonquian Dependent Nouns and Medial Finals, S: 85; 160.0 p. (Box 22)
  - Penobscot-Algonquian Linguistic Notes, Comparisons, n.d.; S: 86; 26.0 p.
  - Penobscot-Algonquian Roots and Reconstructions, S: 82-84; 3.0 folders
    - Volume 1, n.d.; S: 82; 236.0 p.
    - Volume 2, n.d.; S: 83; 212.0 p.
    - Volume 3, n.d.; S: 84; 192.0 p.
  - Penobscot Conjunct Verb Forms, n.d.; S: 53; 149.0 p.
  - Penobscot Grammar #2, n.d.; S: 74; 229.0 p.
    Paradigms (TA subjunctive endings); vowels; vowel syncope
  - Penobscot Grammar Notes #1, n.d.; S: 71; 247.0 p.
    Old Penobscot materials; word sets; noun and derived verb of being (lists, forms)
  - Penobscot Grammar Notes #2, n.d.; S: 72; 243.0 p.
  - Penobscot Grammatical Notes, 1936; S: 48; 82.0 p.
    Stories in English, grammar, words
  - Penobscot Grammatical Sketch, n.d.; S: 73; 232.0 p.
    Syncope, accent; historical notes; Eastern Abenaki dialects, history
  - Penobscot Language Notes, 1935; S: 46; 80.0 p.
    Andrew Dana
  - Penobscot Miscellaneous Notes, Vocabulary, etc., 1969; S: 57; 271.0 p.
    Andrew Dana. Western Abenaki (St. Francis, Odanak) from John Harrington
  - Penobscot Notebook, n.d.; S: 80; 108.0 p. (Box 22)
  - Penobscot Notes, 1935; 84.0 p.
    Notes on texts, speakers, history, vocabulary
  - Penobscot Notes, 1937-1938; 80.0 p. (Box 17)
    Notebook marked: "#10." Stories: A. Dana; Marriage Customs; Burial Dances; Shamanism; Childrens Teeth; Divination (Hunting); Taboo on Deerhoofs or Legs; Halo Around the Moon; No Pitfalls Used by Penobscot; Names of Thunderers; Thunder Beings; Community Spirit (Social Cooperation); Penobscot Belief in Thunderstone; Taboo and Joking Relationship; Areas in a Wigwam; Catching Fish; Smoking; Character Traits of Animals in Animal Stories; Shamans Tricks; Measuring Time; Some vocabulary
  - Penobscot Notes: How Bumole Came to Meddybemps, Lots of Vocabulary, 1935; S: 27; 80.0 p.
    Joe Swansson text and extensive vocabulary; Sylvia Stanislaus
  - Penobscot Notes, 1936; S: 37; 80.0 p.
    Words, ethnography
  - Penobscot Notes, 1936; S: 43; 67.0 p.
    Notes from Newell Gabriel
  - Penobscot Notes: Trout Brook, Pine Clusters, White Deer, The Frog, 1936; S: 45; 76.0 p.
  - Penobscot Notes, 1936; S: 47; 78.0 p.
    Francis Stanislaus, Sylvia Stanislaus
  - Penobscot Notes, 1936; S: 49; 80.0 p.
    Newell Gabriel
  - Penobscot Notes: Months, Vocabulary, 1939; S: 50; 43.0 p.
    Also includes ethnographic notes
  - Penobscot Notes: Family and Place Names, 1935; S: 51; 71.0 p.
  - Penobscot Paradigms, n.d.; S: 75; 19.0 p.
    TI Class 1
  - Penobscot Phonemes and Sound System, 1936; S: 52; 76.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 1; 72.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 2; 70.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 3; 98.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 4; 99.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Shining Alone (continued), Story of Galoskabe and the Beaver and Muskrat, Trading Tails, 1951; S: 5; 52.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Beaver and the Muskrat (Gluskabe Text Continued), 1952-1953; S: 6; 158.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, 1954-1955; S: 7; 151.0 p.
    Includes Little Pelvis Bone
  - Penobscot Texts, 1957; S: 8; 100.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, 1957; S: 9; 105.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 10; 115.0 p.
    Includes list of Famous Raconteurs of Penobscots
  - Penobscot Texts, 1936; S: 11; 80.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts, 1939; S: 12; 23.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: White Tree, or Origin of Flagroot, n.d.; S: 13; 30.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Bumole #1, n.d.; S: 14; 10.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Arrowhead Fingernails, 1931; S: 15; 38.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Mighty Traveller, n.d.; S: 16; 33.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Moose Family and Mohawk Chief, 1937; S: 17; 142.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: End of Mohawk Chief, 1937; S: 18; 78.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Norridgewock Fight, 1934-1935; S: 19; 149.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Bears, 1935; S: 20; 123.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Hairless Bear, 1935-1936; S: 21; 125.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: White Deer, Pamole, n.d.; S: 22; 55.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Origin of Fire, 1936; S: 24; 48.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Ida Gould Notes, Ghost Hunter, Barter Game Notes, True Story, 1936; S: 25; 51.0 p.
  - Penobscot Texts: Origin / Theft of Fire, n.d.; S: 26; 26.0 p.
    Relates to S: 24
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 32; 55.0 p.
    Kathie Ranco, Sylvia Stanislaus (revision of text), Ida Gould
  - Penobscot Texts: Witch Story of Saphonic Lake, 1936; S: 35; 72.0 p.
    Also includes vocabulary, animal family totems. Emma Ranco
  - Penobscot Texts, 1936; S: 36; 92.0 p. (Box 17)
    Despite title, notebook consists largely of cultural notes, vocabulary, and texts.
    - Wampum belt designs, 1936
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 41; 9.0 p.
    Includes words, song
  - Penobscot Texts: Ocean Islands, S: 42; 4.0 p.
    Includes 200-word vocabulary list
  - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; S: 85; 270.0 p.
    Includes Pretty Legs, Gluskabe and the Pleated Woodpecker, Related Roots, Gluskabe and Partridge, Gluskabe Visits his Uncle Turtle, Grammar Notes. Cites some Fox forms
  - Penobscot Vocabulary, 1932-1935; S: 23; 160.0 p.
    Primarily vocabulary: Bird names; Mammals; Trees, Plants, Flowers, etc.; words from Louis Lolar; Gluskabe and his Grandmother ("first Indian text ever taken by me from Indian dictation"), etc.
  - Penobscot Vocabulary, 1938; S: 34; 74.0 p.
  - Penobscot Vocabulary, n.d.; S: 56; 232.0 p.
  - Penobscot Vocabulary Collected from Lewis Lolar, 1932; 116.0 p.
  - Penobscot Vocabulary Developed from Myths, 1986; 52.0 p.
  - Pocket Notebook, 1935; 32.0 p.
    Includes census data of Algonquian groups, list of Oklahoma speakers, Stockbridge Mahicans, information on Siebert's western trip in 1935, etc.
  - Polly Wildcat, Cherokee, 1940; 31.0 p.
    Includes vocabulary in Cherokee and Quapaw
  - Research Notes, n.d.; S: 79; 107.0 p. (Box 18)
    Notes on the Maine Indian Census of 1708, placename vocabulary, historical notes, etc.
  - Research Notes, n.d.; S: 81; 133.0 p.
    Villieu narrative (1694), French and English; notes on historical phonology; Penobscot vowel syncope
  - Roots in: n, m, w, 1964; 173.0 p.
  - Scribble-in Book, 1934-1935; 90.0 p.
    Maliseet, Penobscot vocabulary. Montagnais, Lake St. John (Pointe Bleue); from Andrew Gunner. Note about S[ylvia] S[tanislaus]. Includes later corrections
  - Sentence Types #1, Demonstrative Sentences, [1960-1979]; S: 60; 219.0 p.
    Andrew Dana, Susie Dana
  - Sentence Types #2, Miscellaneous Vocabulary, n.d.; S: 61; 218.0 p.
  - Sentence Types #3, Miscellaneous Vocabulary, n.d.; S: 62; 246.0 p.
  - Sentence Types #4, n.d.; S: 63; 265.0 p.
    Penobscot. Susie Dana ("all this book S. D."). Placenames
  - Sentence Types #5, Miscellaneous Vocabulary, n.d.; S: 64; 242.0 p.
    Penobscot demonstrative pronouns; elicited sentences (Susie Dana); Massachusetts passages; months
  - Translation Book, n.d.; S: 70; 74.0 p.
    Penobscot. Particles; paradigms; enclitics; word sets
  - Translation Book - Inserts, n.d.; S: 70-A; 174.0 p.
    Loose papers found inserted in Translation Book (S: 70)
  - Tribal Population Notes, n.d.; 25.0 p.
    Delaware, Caughnawaga, Abenaki, Huron, Penobscot, Mohawk, Mississagua
  - Tribe Classification and Notes, 30.0 p.
    Books and Material, Iroquois Words, Susquehannocks, Tribal Classification, Omaha Tribal Prayer, Massachusetts, Chiefs of Wampanoags, Chiefs of Narragansetts, Pennsylvania Facts & Historical Notes, etc.
- VI. Works by Siebert
- VII. Works by Others
  - Accent, 1973; 14.0 p.; Allen, W. Sidney, (William Sidney), b. 1918 (Box 28)
    Chapter from Allen, Accent and Rhythym: Prosodic Features of Latin and Greek (Cambridge, 1973).
  - Head Start gets Satisfaction the Navajo Way, 1997; 2.0 p.; Becenti, Deenise (Box 8)
    Navajo Times, vol. XXXVI, no. 29
- VIII. Professional Records
- IX. Book Collecting
  - Executive Council Minutes, n.d.; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 15)
- X. Printed Material
- XI. Audio Recordings
- Graphics
  - Cherokee child, 1900
  - Iroquois family, 1984-1985